<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <channel>
        <title>Braneshop | braneshop.com.au</title>
        <link>https://braneshop.com.au</link>
        <description><![CDATA[The blog of the Braneshop team.]]></description>
        <atom:link href="https://braneshop.com.au/rss.xml" rel="self"
                   type="application/rss+xml" />
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 UT</lastBuildDate>
        <item>
    <title>Braneshop &mdash; "A Living Business" - Part 2 of 3</title>
    <link>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/Braneshop-A-Living-Business-Part-2.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[


  <center> <p> <img src="https://braneshop.com.au/images/blog/living-business/living-business.png" width="100%" /> 
  <br /><small>A summary of the key aspects of the Braneshop business.</small></p> </center>


<ul class="normal">
<li>
<a href="/posts/Braneshop-A-Living-Business-Part-1.html">Part 1 of 3 - Inspiration</a>
</li>
<li>
<a href="/posts/Braneshop-A-Living-Business-Part-2.html">Part 2 of 3 - The Idea: A Living Business</a> (this page)
</li>
<li>
(Coming soon!) Part 3 of 3 - Patterns for Braneshop
</li>
</ul>
<p>This post is inspired by the ideas laid out in <a href="/posts/Braneshop-A-Living-Business-Part-1">first post in this series</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/Braneshop-A-Living-Business-Part-2.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Braneshop Team</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Introduction to Explainable AI - 6th of Nov, 2019</title>
    <link>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/Introduction-To-Explainable-AI-Event.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[


  <center> <p> <img src="https://braneshop.com.au/images/blog/xai-event.webp" width="100%" /> 
  <br /><small>Join us for an evening of Explainable AI!</small></p> </center>


<center>
<i> <a href="https://events.humanitix.com.au/making-the-black-box-of-ai-transparent-with-explainable-ai-xai">Join us on the 6th of November for an Introduction to Explainable AI - Opening the black box!</a> </i>
</center>
<p>From talking to people across different businesses for the last few months, we know that there is significant interest in “exaplainble” AI models. The reason is natural: When we deploy these decision-making tools, we need to understand <em>why</em> they make decisions; as this helps us learn if they are doing the “right” thing. And furthermore, it let’s us improve or adjust our processes.</p>
<p>Our intention is to give you a high-level overview, and cover one or two areas in some detail, so you can get a feel for what’s involved.</p>
<p>As such, we’ve organised an event to explore the landscape of Explainable AI. In particular, we will:</p>
<ul>
<li>Look at what’s available,</li>
<li>Work out what is involved in applying it,</li>
<li>and, Learn where the field is heading!</li>
</ul>
<p>We’re bringing together a few people in Melbourne who are doing interesting work in this area!</p>
<p>After attending this event, you should be able to understand:</p>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/Introduction-To-Explainable-AI-Event.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Braneshop Team</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Braneshop &mdash; "A Living Business" - Part 1 of 3</title>
    <link>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/Braneshop-A-Living-Business-Part-1.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[


  <center> <p> <img src="https://braneshop.com.au/images/blog/living-business/braneshop-inspo.png" width="100%" /> 
  <br /><small>Inspirations for a different way of thinking about the Braneshop business.</small></p> </center>


<ul class="normal">
<li>
<a href="/posts/Braneshop-A-Living-Business-Part-1.html">Part 1 of 3 - Inspiration</a> (this page)
</li>
<li>
<a href="/posts/Braneshop-A-Living-Business-Part-2.html">Part 2 of 3 - The Idea: A Living Business</a>
</li>
<li>
(Coming soon!) Part 3 of 3 - Patterns for Braneshop
</li>
</ul>
<p>As the year draws to a close, and Braneshop is almost a year old (woo!) we have been thinking a lot about our business goals. As such, I (Noon) have been having some discussions with different people and businesses about how Braneshop could align and/or collaborate with their businesses, naturally this has lead into a lot of conversations about where Braneshop is “heading”.</p>
<p>The question is this: What kind of business is Braneshop? How do I see it changing over the years? What are our aims?</p>
<p>After thinking about it for a while, I think it’s nicely captured by the idea of what I’m going to call “A Living Business”.</p>
<p>What does that mean?! In the following blog two blog posts, I’ll talk about what inspired it and what it means to us. We welcome you to reach beyond the usual business comfort-zone and read on!</p>
<p>First up, in this post, we’ll explore the inspirations. I start by introducing them and then end with what we define as “A Living Business”. (If you want to skip straight to the details, you may do so by clicking <a href="/posts/Braneshop-A-Living-Business-Part-2.html">here</a>.)</p>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/Braneshop-A-Living-Business-Part-1.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Braneshop Team</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Non-Technical, But Detailed, Explanation of Our Business Card Designs!</title>
    <link>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/Non-Technical-But-Detailed-Explanation-Of-Our-Business-Card-Designs.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[


  <center> <p> <img src="https://braneshop.com.au/images/blog/business-cards.jpg" width="100%" /> 
  <br /><small>An assorted collection of our new business cards!</small></p> </center>


<p>Our new business cards arrived earlier this week, and since showing them around to a few people and getting some very nice feedback, I thought it might be of interest to talk a bit about how they were made.</p>
<p>In particular I wanted to aim this discussion at people who are not intimately familiar with making graphics on computers.</p>
<p>Let’s get into it!</p>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/Non-Technical-But-Detailed-Explanation-Of-Our-Business-Card-Designs.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Braneshop Team</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Scholarships for August Technical Deep Learning Workshop Close on Sunday!</title>
    <link>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/Aug-2019-Scholarships-Close-On-Sunday.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[
<p>Video summary:</p>
<center>
  <iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/349597581" width="800" height="400" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen></iframe>
  <p>Watch on Vimeo - <a href="https://player.vimeo.com/video/349597581">Note on scholarships.</a></p>
</center>




<p>Ruth and I are very pleased to be offering scholarships for our workshop coming up on the 8th of August. We’ve already accept first-round scholarships (6 people), and so there are some remaining places.</p>
<p>We’re encouraging applications from anyone that has typically faced barriers in their career/learning in the tech industry. One of our big aims at Braneshop is to increase the representation in the AI industry, and this is one way we’re working towards that goal.</p>
<p>You can find the application form here: <a href="https://noonvandersilk.typeform.com/to/Tnfm4a">Scholarship for the 6 Week Technical Deep Learning Workshop</a>, and of course more details about the workshop itself here: <a href="/6-week-workshop-on-deep-learning.html">6 Week Workshop</a>.</p>
<p>We’ve also got a scholarship for the <a href="/ai-for-leadership.html">AI For Leadership Workshop</a>, coming up in September. This is an important one for us as well, as, in order to see change broadly through-out the industry, we will need change in leadership positions.</p>
<p>Here at the Braneshop we’re creating a welcoming and supportive community for everyone to be involved in AI. We hope you join us!</p>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/Aug-2019-Scholarships-Close-On-Sunday.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Braneshop Team</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Deep learning showreel now online!</title>
    <link>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/Showreel-Online.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[


  <center> <p> <img src="https://braneshop.com.au/images/showreel/Understanding and Predicting Visual Humour.jpg" width="100%" /> 
  <br /><small><a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1512.04407.pdf">My favourite paper of 2015</a>, and maybe of all time. See the <a href="/showreel.html">showreel</a> page for more!</small></p> </center>


<p>We love staying up to date with the latest deep learning research. I typically catch up daily, via the <a href="https://scirate.com">SciRate</a> website (check if out if you haven’t already!)</p>
<p>Every now and then, a paper really stands out as either cool, interesting, innovative, or useful. When something really appealed to me, I’d typically post it in various places, such as LinkedIn, or slack, or twitter, or just file it away in my head, waiting for the perfect moment to pop up again.</p>
<p>We also typically include these as part of the workshops, to get people a bit excited about the field.</p>
<p>Well, now I’ve decided to put that list online: <a href="/showreel.html">Deep learning showreel!</a></p>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/Showreel-Online.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Braneshop Team</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>State of the art attention models in PyText - Part 1</title>
    <link>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/State-of-the-art-attention-models-in-PyText-Part-1.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[
<p>Video summary:</p>
<center>
  <iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/347859684" width="800" height="400" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen></iframe>
  <p>Watch on Vimeo - <a href="https://player.vimeo.com/video/347859684">Braneshop - Attention in PyText - Part 1</a></p>
</center>



  <center> <p> <img src="https://braneshop.com.au/images/blog/at_1.jpg" width="100%" /> 
  <br /><small>Attention being computed across a custom-dataset and being dsiplayed in TensorBoard!</small></p> </center>


<p>I wanted to take some time to discuss a library that seems to have flown under the radar a little bit. It’s called <a href="https://github.com/facebookresearch/pytext">PyText</a>, and we’re going to explore how you can use it to run state of the art attention models!</p>
<p>Here’s our plan:</p>
<ol style="list-style-type: decimal">
<li>Set a dataset,</li>
<li>See how we prepare the data for training in PyText,</li>
<li>Get PyText,</li>
<li>Train it,</li>
<li>Visualise it,</li>
<li>Consider extensions,</li>
</ol>
<p>Finally, we’ll jump in to a fork of PyText where I’ve added a few features that help out during training.</p>
<p>If you want to follow along, all the code for this post is available <a href="https://github.com/Braneshop/pytext">here</a>.</p>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/State-of-the-art-attention-models-in-PyText-Part-1.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Braneshop Team</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Venue for the first workshop - BlueRock!</title>
    <link>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/2019-06-28-First-workshop-at-Blue-Rock.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[


  <center> <p> <img src="https://braneshop.com.au/images/blog/BlueRock.jpg" width="100%" /> 
  <br /><small>The <a href="https://thebluerock.com.au/" rel="noopener">BlueRock</a> offices.</small></p> </center>


<p>We’re very grateful to the very nice people at <a
href="https://thebluerock.com.au/" rel="noopener">BlueRock</a> (be sure to check out their website!) who have agreed to be our venue hosts for the upcoming <a
href="/6-week-workshop-on-deep-learning.html">6 week technical deep learning workshop</a>, kicking off on the 8th of August!</p>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/2019-06-28-First-workshop-at-Blue-Rock.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Braneshop Team</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Deep learning quick start</title>
    <link>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/2019-06-21-Deep-learning-quick-start.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[



<p>It’s been in vogue for some time now to have a little “quick-start” install on your website. Notable examples are:</p>
<ul class="normal">
<li>
The <a href="https://spacy.io/usage" rel="noopener">spaCy</a> website,
</li>
<li>
<a href="https://pytorch.org/" rel="noopener">PyTorch</a>.
</li>
</ul>
<p>My friend Hayden suggested that it might be nice to have a slightly higher-level one, so I made it: <a href="/quickstart.html">Braneshop deep learning quick start</a>, and you can find a link to it at the bottom of the page.</p>
<p>The main thing I wanted to get across, for whatever it’s worth, is that one of your best options is <a href="https://colab.research.google.com/">Google Colaboratory</a>. The other thing I did was to just collect together the information from the TensorFlow and the PyTorch installation pages.</p>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/2019-06-21-Deep-learning-quick-start.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Braneshop Team</dc:creator>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Ruth joins Braneshop, and new workshop launch!</title>
    <link>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/2019-06-09-Ruth-joins-Braneshop-and-Workshop-Launch.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[


  <center> <p> <img src="https://braneshop.com.au/images/ruth-whiteboard.jpg" width="100%" /> 
  <br /><small>Me (Ruth!) teaching neural networks at the <a href="http://womeninai.com.au">Women in AI</a> leadership course in Brisbane, 2019.</small></p> </center>


<p>Hello friends!</p>
<p>This is your first Braneshop blog post from me, and I’m very excited to be writing it to tell you about our first <a href="/6-week-workshop-on-deep-learning.html">6 Week Technical Deep Learning Workshop</a> scheduled to start on the 8th of August, which is <a href="https://events.humanitix.com.au/braneshop-6-week-technical-deep-learning-workshop">on sale now!</a></p>
<p>(Not to mention our first <a href="/ai-for-leadership.html">AI for Leadership</a> workshop which is also on sale now, and our <a href="/deep-learning-workshop.html">Intensive Technical Deep Learning Workshop</a> which we can bring to your organisation — <a href="https://noonvandersilk.typeform.com/to/DYKvWN">get in touch!</a>)</p>
<p>I recently joined my friend Noon at Braneshop as an instructor, here’s why:</p>
]]></description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 00:00:00 UT</pubDate>
    <guid>https://braneshop.com.au/posts/2019-06-09-Ruth-joins-Braneshop-and-Workshop-Launch.html</guid>
    <dc:creator>Braneshop Team</dc:creator>
</item>

    </channel>
</rss>
